Finding Aid for the American Civil Liberties Union of Southern California Records LSC.0900
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Archive, 1980-1985
  - ___ ____. Objections to Findings and Conclusions. (Box 383)
  - Plan 3. (Box 384)
  - IEEC. Volume 6. Appendix 26. (Box 384)
  - ___ ____. Volume 7. Appendix 26 (cont.). (Box 384)
  - Metro. (Box 385)
  - Dallas Brief. (Box 385)
  - IEEC. Appendix 7. Value Analysis System. (Box 385)
  - Bustop. (Box 386)
  - ___ ____. (Box 386)
  - ___ ____. (Box 386)
  - Rosenbaum. Experts. Orfield. (Box 387)
  - ___ ____. Coleman. (Box 387)
  - ___ ____. (Box 388)
  - ___ ____. (Box 388)
  - ___ ____. Pettigrew. (Box 388)
  - ___ ____. Ross. (Box 389)
  - ___ ____. Taylor. (Box 389)
  - ___ ____. Board Experts. Norman Miller. (Box 389)
  - ___ ____. Powell-Cottle. Social Science Articles. (Box 389)
  - ___ ____. Fiedler, Ferraro, Weintraub. (Box 389)
  - Guidelines for Expert Witnesses. (Box 389)
  - White Flight. (Box 389)
  - Data Relating to School Integration. (Box 390)
  - SETSI Minutes. (Box 390)
  - Appeal Briefs. (Box 390)
  - Metropolitanization. State Financial Relief. (Box 390)
  - Final Briefs. (Box 391)
  - Proposition I. (Box 391)
  - Bilingual. (Box 392)
  - Exhibits. (Box 392)
  - Argument Ideas. (Box 392)
  - RIMS. Witnesses, Experts. (Box 392)
  - School Listings/Councils. (Box 392)
  - Ghetto, Barrio. (Box 393)
  - Budget. (Box 393)
  - Hamilton-Rabinovitz. (Box 393)
  - Proficiency Tests. (Box 394)
  - Correspondence. (Box 394)
  - Desegregating LAUSD. First Simulation Series. Volume 1. (Box 394)
  - ___ ____. Second Simulation Series. Volume 1. (Box 394)
  - Opening Brief of Crawford et. al. On Appeal from Order., July 7, 1980 (Box 395)
  - Examination of David Garth Taylor. (Box 395)
  - Appendix to First Appellant's Opening Brief. Appeal Order. (Box 395)
  - ___ ____. (Box 395)
  - Exhibits in Support of Brief A/C, Petitioners. (Box 395)
  - Exhibit B to District's Proposed Master Plan for Relief of Overcrowding. (Box 396)
  - ___ ____. (Box 396)
  - ___ ____. (Box 396)
  - High School Plan. (Box 396)
  - Dismantlement. (Box 396)
  - RIMS. Site Committees. (Box 396)
  - Teacher Integration. (Box 396)
  - Wickline. (Box 396)
  - Work Completed. (Newspaper Clippings.). (Box 397)
  - Program for Minority Schools. Critique of Board Plan. Board Experts and Community and Parties. (Box 397)
  - RIMS. Law. (Box 397)
  - Davies. (Box 397)
  - Thomas. (Box 397)
  - Rosenbaum. School Profiles. (Box 398)
  - ___ ____. Principals. (Box 398)
  - Crawford. Supreme Court. Resource Material. (Box 399)
  - Appendix to First Appellant's Reply to Plaintiff's Brief. Volume 4. (Box 399)
  - Crawford. Supreme Court. Briefs. (Box 400)
  - ___ ____. Resource Material. (Box 400)
  - ___ ____. Briefs. (Box 401)
  - ___ ____. Appeal File. Legal Research. (Box 401)
  - ___ ____. (Box 401)
  - ___ ____. (Box 402)
  - ___ ____. (Box 402)
  - Crawford vs. Board of Education. File 1882.2. (Box 402)
  - ___ ____. (Box 402)
  - ___ ____. (Box 402)
  - Bustop Materials. (Box 403)
  - Ethnic Analysis by School., 10/76. (Box 403)
  - LAUSD Citizens' Advisory Committee on School Integration. (Box 403)
  - ___ ____. (Box 403)
  - ___ ____. (Box 403)
  - ___ ____. (Box 403)
  - School Desegregation, Levinsohn, ed. (Box 403)
  - American Bar Foundation Research Journal, no. 4., 1976 (Box 403)
  - Integrated Education. (Box 404)
  - Citizen Guide to Desegregation. (Box 404)
  - Statement on Metropolitan School Desegregation. (Box 404)
  - The Shame of Los Angeles. (Box 404)
  - Sociology of Education. (Box 404)
  - To Kill a Child's Spirit. (Box 404)
  - School Segregation on our Doorstep. (Box 404)
  - Fulfilling the Letter and Spirit of the Law. (Box 404)
  - Three Myths: An Exposure of Popular Misconceptions about School Desegregation. (Box 404)
  - The Development of a School Integration Plan in Riverside, California. (Box 404)
  - Crawford vs. Board of Education. General Files. (Box 405)
  - ___ ____. (Box 405)
  - ___ ____. (Box 405)
  - ___ ____. (Box 405)
  - ___ ____. (Box 405)
  - ___ ____. (Box 405)
  - Crawford. Miscellaneous Legal Materials. (Box 406)
  - Equality of Educational Opportunity. Coleman. (Box 406)
  - Supplementary Index to the Survey on Equality of Educational Opportunity. (Box 406)
  - Crawford II. School Board Plan. (Box 407)
  - ___ ____. Spotlight. (Box 407)
  - Preparations for final argument. (Box 407)
  - Proposed interrogatories. (Box 407)
  - Crawford. Correspondence. (Box 407)
  - ___ ____. (Box 407)
  - Plan for the Integration of Pupils. Volume 1. (Box 407)
  - Title I. (Box 408)
  - Budget. (Box 408)
  - Title IV. (Box 408)
  - Title VII. (Box 408)
  - Bilingual. (Box 408)
  - Crawford. Medvene's Notes re Intervention. (Box 408)
  - Barsky vs. Weinberger. Interrogatories. (Box 408)
  - Crawford. Definitions. (Box 408)
  - ___ ____. Survey. (Box 408)
  - ___ ____. News Articles. (Box 408)
  - San Diego Case. Pleadings. (Box 408)
  - Riverside. (Box 409)
  - ___ ____. (Box 409)
  - ___ ____. (Box 409)
  - Correspondence. EMM. (Box 409)
  - ___ ____. (Box 409)
  - Deposition Digests. (Box 410)
  - ___ ____. (Box 410)
  - ___ ____. (Box 410)
  - ___ ____. (Box 410)
  - Desegregation Cases. (Box 410)
  - Crawford. Witness File. (Box 411)
  - ___ ____. (Box 411)
  - Desegregation Cases. Cleveland, Michigan, Nevada. (Box 411)
  - Desegregation Material. (Box 411)
  - Desegregation Cases. Memphis, Austin, Newport News, Denver, Charlotte, Oklahoma. (Box 411)
  - Miscellaneous Supreme Court. (Box 411)
  - Miscellaneous Court Procedure. (Box 411)
  - Desegregation. California. (Box 412)
  - ___ ____. Connecticut, New York, South Carolina, Texas, Ohio. (Box 412)
  - Miscellaneous Supreme Court Cases. (Box 412)
  - Stay Cases. (Box 412)
  - Respondents' Crawford et. al. Petition for Hearing. (Box 412)
  - Board of Education's Answer to Petition for Hearing. (Box 413)
  - Stay Cases. (Box 413)
  - LAUSD Plan for Desegregation. (Box 413)
  - Exhibits. (Box 414)
  - Miscellaneous Crawford. (Box 414)
  - ___ ____. Desegregation Cases. (Box 414)
  - Mike Stolle. (Box 414)
  - Titles I and VII. (Box 414)
  - Miscellaneous Documents. Mostly ACLU. (Box 414)
  - ___ ____. (Box 415)
  - ___ ____. (Box 415)
  - ___ ____. (Box 415)
  - ___ ____. (Box 415)
  - LAUSD CACSI Preliminary Report, Integration Plan,., March 18, 1977. (Box 415)
  - Busing. Rand. (Box 416)
  - Miscellaneous Articles. (Box 416)
  - ___ ____. (Box 416)
  - Background Material. (Box 416)
  - Board of Education. Minutes. (Box 416)
  - Medvene Closing Argument Material. (Box 416)
  - Jose Cardenas. (Box 417)
  - Harold Gerard. (Box 417)
  - Alfred S. Moore. (Box 417)
  - ___ ____. (Box 417)
  - Elizabeth Cohen. (Box 417)
  - Elliot Aronson. (Box 417)
  - CACSI. (Box 418)
  - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights. (Box 418)
  - Dr. Norman Miller. (Box 418)
  - Caughey Materials. (Box 418)
  - ___ ____. (Box 418)
  - ___ ____. (Box 418)
  - ___ ____. (Box 418)
- Archive, 1986
  The following records were deposited in 1986. Boxes 419-627 cover the case Crawford vs. Board of Education. As in previous entries, some material covers earlier dates.
  - Crawford vs. L.A. City Board of Education. Integration Plans. 1977 et seq. (Box 419)
  - Crawford. Integration Impact Statement. (Box 420)
  - Crawford vs. L.A. City Board of Education. Law. (Box 420)
  - Crawford vs. L.A. City Board of Education. Law #2. (Box 420)
  - Crawford vs. L.A. City Board of Education. Law #2 cont. (Box 421)
  - Crawford vs. L.A. City Board of Education. Intervention 1977. (Box 421)
  - Crawford vs. L.A. City Board of Education. Intervention 1977. #2. (Box 422)
  - Crawford vs. L.A. City Board of Education. Monitoring Committee Reports. (Box 422)
  - Crawford vs. L.A. City Board of Education. Motion to Disqualify Judge Egly. (Box 422)
  - UTL Intervention. 1979. (Box 423)
  - Crawford vs. Board of Education. Post S.Ct. July 1976 Decision. Task Force for Desegregation. (Box 423)
  - Exhibits to Respondent's Answers to Judge Egly's 22 Questions. (Box 423)
  - Sup. Ct. Intended Order. (Box 423)
  - Crawford. Miscellaneous. (Box 423)
  - B.O.E. City of L.A. Minutes and Attachments of Meeting of Governing Board of Jan. 17, Mar. 3, Mar. 17. 1977 (Box 424)
  - B.O.E. City of L.A. Draft for March 1977 Submission. (Box 424)
  - B.O.E. City of L.A. (Box 424)
  - IEEC. Volume III. (Box 424)
  - Controller's Annual Financial Report. (Box 424)
  - 13th Annual Financial Forecast. (Box 424)
  - 14th Annual Financial Forecast. (Box 424)
  - March 1977 Plan. Volume III. (Box 425)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Miscellaneous. 1968 et seq. (Box 425)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Extra Copies of Pleadings, Petitioner's Memoranda, &c. (Box 425)
  - Crawford I. Gitelson Materials. (Box 426)
  - Crawford I. Special Reading Materials. (Box 426)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Legal Research and Materials. 1966 et seq. (Box 427)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Exhibits 4-22. (Box 427)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Exhibits 47-57. (Box 427)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Exhibits 60-69. (Box 427)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Exhibits 74-83. (Box 427)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Exhibits 85-102. (Box 427)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Exhibits 103-110. (Box 427)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Exhibits 129-132, 136, 139. (Box 427)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Post S. Ct. June 1976. Court Papers. Vol I. 8/31/63 to March 1977. (Box 428)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Post S. Ct. June 1976. Court Papers. Vol II. 3/19/77 to 4/25/77. (Box 428)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Post S. Ct. June 1976. Court Papers. Vol III. 3/31/77 to 5/31/77. (Box 428)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Post S. Ct. June 1976. Court Papers. Vol IV. 5/16/77 to 6/18/77. (Box 429)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Post S. Ct. June 1976. Court Papers. Vol. V. 6/6/77 to 6/16/77. (Box 429)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Post S. Ct. June 1976. Court Papers. Vol. VI. 6/13/77 to 7/21/77. (Box 430)
  - Reporter's Transcript on Appeal. Vol. 55-57. (Box 430)
  - Reporter's Transcript on Appeal. Vol. 58, 59. (Box 430)
  - Crawford I. (Box 431)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Pleadings. 3/77 to 6/77. (Box 432)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Pleadings. 5/77 to 6/77. (Box 432)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Pleadings. Undated. (Box 433)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Pleadings. Tape Transcripts. (Box 433)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Attorney's Notes. (Box 434)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. RIMS. Principal/ Teacher Selection. (Box 434)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. RIMS. Curriculum. (Box 434)
  - Principals/Teachers. Interviews, Name Lists. (Box 434)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Lieberman. (Box 435)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Orfield. (Box 435)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Court Papers. (Box 436)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Copies of Respondent's Opening Brief, 8/15/69. Respondent's Position re Equal Black Opportunity, 5/1/69. (Box 436)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Newsclippings. (Box 436)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Desegregation Materials. (Box 436)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Respondent's Reply Brief. (Box 437)
  - Miscellaneous Materials. (Box 437)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Summary of Transcripts. Vol. 1-21. (Box 438)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Summary of Transcripts. Vol. 22-42. (Box 438)
  - NDN. Educational Programs that Work. (Box 438)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Summary of Transcripts. Vol. 43-64. (Box 439)
  - Tape Recording of Nov. 27, 1963 BOE Meeting. (Box 439)
  - Crawford Appeal File. William T. Rintala Personal File. 1970-72. (Box 440)
  - Crawford Appeal File. Caughey Materials. (Box 440)
  - Crawford I. 1882.2. Materials. (Box 440)
  - Crawford I. 1882.2. Litigation File. (Box 440)
  - Crawford I. (Box 441)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. 1882.2. File #1. 1967. (Box 442)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. 1882.2. File #2. 1/1/68 to 6/30/68. (Box 442)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. 1882.2. File #3. 6/1/68 to 1/72. (Box 442)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. 1882.2. File #3. (Box 443)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. 1882.2. File #4. 2/1/72 to 7/31/73. (Box 443)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. 1882.2. File #6. 1 Jan. 1979 et seq. (Box 443)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. 1882.2. File #6 cont. (Box 444)
  - Deposition. Celia Rodriguez. 4/5/68. (Box 444)
  - Deposition. Kaye M. Wheeler. 4/16/68. (Box 444)
  - Deposition. Loretta May. 7/22/68. (Box 444)
  - Deposition. Josefa Sanchez. 6/13/68. (Box 444)
  - Deposition. Annie Mary Miles. 4/25/68. (Box 444)
  - Deposition. Dollie Ruth Miles. 7/2/68. (Box 444)
  - Deposition. Alexander J. Sanchez/ 8/22/68. (Box 444)
  - Deposition. Lucille May. 4/4/68. (Box 444)
  - Kimball/ Kimbrough. (Box 444)
  - PWT Cases. (Box 444)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Trial Exhibits. R372 Series. (Box 445)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Trial Exhibits. R376 Series. (Box 445)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Trial Exhibits. R373 Series. (Box 445)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Trial Exhibits. Miscellaneous Respondent's Exhibits. (Box 445)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Trial Exhibits. Petitioner's and Court's Exhibits. (Box 445)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Trial Exhibits. R383, 379 Series. (Box 445)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Trial Exhibits. R375 Series. (Box 446)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Trial Exhibits. Miscellaneous Petitioner's Exhibits. (Box 446)
  - Miscellaneous Materials. (Box 446)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Miscellaneous Materials. (Box 447)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Respondent's Exhibits. (Box 447)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Miscellaneous Respondent's Exhibits. (Box 448)
  - Evaluation Reports. ESEA Title I. (Exh. R377-F1) (Box 448)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Sup. Ct. Exhibits. Vols. 3-7. Exhibits 15D-H. (Box 449)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Sup. Ct. Exhibits. Vols. 9-14. 15T-15AA. (Box 450)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Sup. Ct. Exhibits. Vols. 24-27-30. (Box 451)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Sup. Ct. Exhibit P43A. (Box 451)
  - Petitioner's Exhibits. P33-53. (Box 452)
  - Petitioner's Exhibits. P47, P53F. (Box 452)
  - Petitioner's Exhibits. Vol 49, 313D-3. (Box 452)
  - Transcript on Appeal. Vol. 60. (Box 452)
  - Crawford Litigation File. Vol 1. (Box 453)
  - Crawford Litigation File. Vol. 2. (Box 453)
  - Crawford Litigation File. Vol 2A. (Box 454)
  - Crawford Litigation File. Vol 4. (Box 454)
  - Appeal Litigation File. #1. (Box 455)
  - Appeal Litigation File. #2. (Box 455)
  - Report of Dr. Bernard Gifford and Others. 11/14/78. (Box 456)
  - Summary of Reports of Court Experts, Report of Gary Orfield, Monitoring Committee Reports 11 and 12. LAUSD. (Box 457)
  - John Caughey. Findings Based on L.A. B.O.E.'s Official Racial and Ethnic Survey of 1979-80. (Box 457)
  - Study of the Emergency School Aid Act Magnet Program. Final Report. (Box 457)
  - J. Michael Ross. The Social Construction of a School Desegregation Controversy. (Box 457)
  - J. Michael Ross. The Boston School Desegregation Crisis. Crawford. Seattle Sup. Ct. (Box 458)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Materials. (Box 459)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Materials (Box 460)
  - A/C Materials (Box 460)
  - A/C Materials, Miscellaneous Materials. (Box 461)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Deposition. Tomas Arciniega and Others. 3/77- 6/77 (Box 462)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Deposition. Ronald R. Edmonds and Others. 3/77- 6/77. (Box 463)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Deposition. Harry Handler and Others. 3/77- 6/77. (Box 464)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Deposition. Julian Nava and Others. 3/77- 6/77. (Box 465)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Deposition. Diane E. Watson and Others. 3/77- 6/77. (Box 466)
  - Crawford I. Notes. (Box 466)
  - Crawford I. Findings and Judgement. (Box 467)
  - Crawford I. Plans 1977. (Box 467)
  - Crawford II. Implementation 1978. (Box 467)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Experts., 1977-1981 (Box 467)
  - Sup. Ct. Reporter's Transcript on Appeal. Vol. A, 1-3, 4,6,7. (Index), of 62., October 1968 et seq. (Box 468)
  - Sup. Ct. Reporter's Transcript on Appeal. Vol. 8,10,11, and 12-14(Index), of 62. (Box 469)
  - Sup. Ct. Reporter's Transcript on Appeal. Vol. 15,17-19, and 20-22 (Index), of 62. (Box 470)
  - Sup. Ct. Reporter's Transcript on Appeal. Vol. 23-25, 26, 32-34. (Index), of 62. (Box 471)
  - Sup. Ct. Reporter's Transcript on Appeal. Vol. 35,37,38,40-42. (Index), of 62. (Box 472)
  - Sup. Ct. Reporter's Transcript on Appeal. Vol. 43-45, 46-48. (Index), of 62. (Box 473)
  - Sup. Ct. Reporter's Transcript on Appeal. Vol. 49-51, 52, 53. (Index), of 62. (Box 474)
  - Opening Brief of Crawford et al. on Appeal from July 7, 1980 Order. Emergency Petition for Writ of Mandate. (Box 474)
  - Copies of Petitioner's Interrogatories. (Box 475)
  - Exhibit Lists. Petitioner's Memo on Attorney's Fees. (Box 475)
  - Recent Cases. (Box 475)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Appellant's Opening Brief. (Box 475)
  - Second Appellate. Respondent's Reply Brief. (Box 476)
  - Deposition. John Michael Ross and Others., 12/77- 3/5/80 (Box 476)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Papers through 1970. Gitelson Decision. (Box 477)
  - Crawford II. Post July 5, 1977. Vol. VII. (Box 477)
  - Crawford II. Post July 5, 1977. Vol. VIII, IX, X., 10/18/77- 12/14/77 (Box 478)
  - Crawford II. Post July 5, 1977. Vol. X, XI, XII., 12/15/77- 1/31/78 (Box 479)
  - Citizen's Legal Defense Alliance. Cal. Supreme Ct. (Box 479)
  - Crawford II. Latham, vs. L.A. B.O.E. (Box 479)
  - Crawford II. Linxwiler vs. State of California and Others. (Box 480)
  - Crawford II. 9th Grade Motion. and Others. (Box 481)
  - Crawford II. Save Our Schools vs. Supreme Court, and Others. (Box 482)
  - Crawford II. Reporter's Transcripts (1977). Index. (Box 483)
  - Crawford II. Reporter's Transcripts (1977). Vol. 2-13., 3/24/77- 4/20/77 (Box 483)
  - Crawford II. Reporter's Transcripts (1977). Vol. 14-22., 4/25/77- 5/5/77 (Box 484)
  - Crawford II. Reporter's Transcripts (1977). Vol. 23-29, 31-35., 5/6/77- 5/24/77 (Box 485)
  - Crawford II. Clerk's Transcripts. Vol. I-IV., 1978 (Box 486)
  - Crawford II. Clerk's Transcripts. Vol. V-VIII., 1978 (Box 487)
  - Crawford II. Clerk's Transcripts. Vol. IX-XII., 1978 (Box 488)
  - Crawford II. Pleadings. Vol. XXVI-XXVIII., 10/11/79-3/18/80 (Box 489)
  - Crawford II. Pleadings. Vol. XXIX, XXX., 3/19/80-4/30/80 (Box 490)
  - Crawford II. Pleadings. Vol. XXXI-XXXIV., 5/2/80- 8/12/80 (Box 491)
  - Crawford II. Pleadings. Vol. XXXV-XXXVII., 8/12/80- 12/19/80 (Box 492)
  - Crawford II. Pleadings. Vol. XXXVIII- XL, 1/14/81- 6/23/81 (Box 493)
  - Crawford II. Pleadings. Vol. XLI, XLII., 6/22/81- 7/3/81 (Box 494)
  - Crawford II. Pleadings. Vol. XLIII-XXLVI., 6/19/81-8/13/81 (Box 495)
  - Crawford II. Pleadings. Vol. XLV-XLVIII, 8/17/81- 3/19/82 (Box 496)
  - B.O.E. Reports. Dr. Thomas Pettigrew and Others., 11/14/78 (Box 497)
  - Deposition. David J. Armor and Others., 3/16/77- 10/26/79 (Box 498)
  - Deposition. Gary Allan Orfield and Others., 12/2/77- 12/8/77 (Box 499)
  - Deposition. Philip Jordan and Others., 11/2/77- 5/15/79 (Box 500)
  - Deposition Digest. (Box 500)
  - Deposition. Philip Jordan and Others., 12/7/77- 1/25/80 (Box 501)
  - Deposition. Charles Richard Caldwell and Others., 3/27/77- 1/22/81 (Box 502)
  - Deposition. Ward Edwards and Others., 12/7/77- 10/9/79 (Box 503)
  - Deposition. Theopolis Kimbrough and Others., 6/4/77- 1/14/80 (Box 504)
  - Deposition. Jerry F. Halverson and Others., 3/18/77- 9/6/79 (Box 505)
  - Deposition. Howard Miller and George T. Edmiston., 9/25/77- 10/8/79 (Box 506)
  - Deposition. John Michael Ross and Thomas F. Pettigrew., 6/5/77- 3/24/80 (Box 507)
  - Deposition. James Taylor and Others., 11/3/77- 3/24/80 (Box 508)
  - Deposition. Michael J. Stolee and Others., 12/2/77- 3/21/80 (Box 509)
  - Deposition. Bobbi Fiedler and Others., 3/14/80-7/20-81 (Box 510)
  - Maps. (Box 511)
  - Deposition. Byron Lewis Kimball and Christine H. Rossell., 4/17/79- 7/10/79 (Box 511)
  - March 1977 Submission. Vol I. (Box 511)
  - March 1977 Submission. Vol II- IVA. (Box 512)
  - Crawford II. Correspondence. Vol I-III. 1977 et seq. (Box 513)
  - Crawford II. Correspondence. Vol IV., 6/18/81 et seq. (Box 514)
  - Crawford. Costs. (Box 514)
  - Temporary Crawford. Chicago. (Box 514)
  - Crawford II. Deposition Notes. (Box 514)
  - Crawford II. Board Deposition Notes. (Box 514)
  - Crawford II. Minute Orders, 8/81. (Box 514)
  - Crawford Materials. (Box 514)
  - Enrollment Decline and School Desegregation in Cleveland. (Box 514)
  - School Desegregation Organizer's Manual. Annotated Bibliography and Summary of Reference Materials. (Box 514)
  - School Desegregation in Ten Communities., 1973 (Box 514)
  - The Diminishing Barrier., 1972 (Box 514)
  - Equal Opportunity in Suburbia., 1974 (Box 514)
  - Five Communities, 1972 (Box 514)
  - Evaluation and Training Institute. Study of the LAUSD. Vol. I,II. (Box 514)
  - Desegregating the LAUSD. First Simulation Series. Vol. I. (Box 515)
  - Desegregating the LAUSD. Second Simulation Series. Vol. I. (Box 515)
  - Proposition I. Legal Counsel; Bell, Hunt, Staff Analysis. (Box 515)
  - SB 1244 (1979). Burden of Proof. (Box 515)
  - Appendix Material. Proposition I. (Box 515)
  - Proposition I. Arnaudo and NAAL Suits in Sacramento, San Bernadino. (Box 516)
  - Proposition I. Copies of Ballot Arguments. (Box 517)
  - Newsclips. Crawford Voucher System, White Flight, Finances, and Others. (Box 517)
  - Clippings. Teacher's Union, Magnets, D/C., and Others. (Box 518)
  - Clippings. Proposition I., No on One. (Box 519)
  - LAUSD Preliminary Ethnic Analysis., Oct. 1976 (Box 519)
  - Crawford. RIMS Exhibits., 3/3/81 et seq. (Box 520)
  - Petitioner's Post-trial Memo. (Box 520)
  - Overcrowding Relief., 11/79 (Box 520)
  - Crawford II. U.S. Supreme Court. Real Parties' Response to Application for Stay. (Box 520)
  - Tinsley vs. Palo Alto USD. Petitioner's Application for A/C Brief. (Box 520)
  - Miscellaneous Proposition I Materials. (Box 520)
  - Golden Gate University Law Review. Vol. 10, 1980. (Box 520)
  - Program for Racially Isolated Minority Schools. (Box 521)
  - Integrated Educational Excellence Through Choice. Vol. I,II, IV-VI. (Box 521)
  - Proposition I. NAACP vs. San Bernadino, 1979-80. (Box 522)
  - Proposition I. Correspondence, BUSTOP Briefs. (Box 522)
  - LAUSD Data Relating to Student Integration. (Box 523)
  - LAUSD of R.Farley and Others. (Box 523)
  - LAUSD B.O.E. and Monitoring Reports. (Box 523)
  - LAUSD B.O.E. and Monitoring Reports (Box 524)
  - B.O.E. RIMS Proposal. (Box 524)
  - RIMS. Report to Sup. Ct. L.A. Regarding Harms of Racial Isolation. (Box 525)
  - RIMS. Report on Physical Facilities, Reports. (Box 525)
  - Crawford II. METRO., 1977-1979. (Box 526)
  - Crawford vs. B.O.E. Extra Copies of Important Pleadings and Papers. (Box 526)
  - Crawford. Hamilton-Rabinovitz. Vol I,II., 1980 (Box 527)
  - Crawford II. Caughey. Vol. I, II., 1977- 1980 (Box 527)
  - Crawford II. Attorney's Fees. Vol. I- III. (Box 528)
  - Crawford II. Attorney's Fees. Vol. IV. (Box 529)
  - Crawford II. Attorney's Fees. (Box 530)
  - Crawford. Newsclips, 1977 et seq. (Box 531)
  - Crawford II. Price Reports. (Box 531)
  - Crawford. Overcrowding. (Box 531)
  - Crawford. Overcrowding. (Box 532)
  - Crawford Simulations, 1979-1980 (Box 532)
  - Crawford. St. Louis. (Box 532)
  - Stolee. (Box 532)
  - Seattle Briefs. (Box 532)
  - Seattle, cont. (Box 533)
  - Crawford II. San Bernadino. (Box 533)
  - Integration Materials. (Box 534)
  - Crawford. Armor. Atlanta. (Box 535)
  - Crawford. Armor. Dallas, Detroit. (Box 535)
  - Crawford. Armor. San Diego, Louisville. (Box 535)
  - Crawford. Armor. Dallas, San Diego, Omaha. (Box 536)
  - Crawford. Armor. Seattle. (Box 536)
  - Armor. General Writings. (Box 537)
  - Armor. Seattle, Pittsburgh. (Box 537)
  - Armor. Omaha. (Box 538)
  - Armor. Omaha, Milwaukee. (Box 539)
  - Crawford. Certiorari. 1981. Vol I-III. (Box 540)
  - Cal. Sup. Ct. Emergency Petition for Writ of Mandate. Related Appeal Pending. (Box 541)
  - Crawford. Petitioner's Exhibits. #335, 336-355. (Box 541)
  - Crawford. Petitioner's Exhibits. #356, 368- 363. (Box 542)
  - Crawford. Petitioner's Exhibits. #363 (9)-(14), 554-561. (Box 543)
  - Offer of Proof re Judicial Criticism of Armor., 11/26/79 (Box 543)
  - Integration Materials. (Box 543)
  - Crawford Survey. (Box 543)
  - Crawford II. BUSTOP, May 1979. Petition for Writ of Prohibition. (Box 544)